<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ms Maya Boueiz | Mathematical Marine Ecology Lab</title>
    <link>/author/ms-maya-boueiz/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/ms-maya-boueiz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ms Maya Boueiz</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Anthony J. Richardson</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue13ec9768477f6aaf9b00b431f1b1817_1426_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ms Maya Boueiz</title>
      <link>/author/ms-maya-boueiz/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Conservation and protected areas</title>
      <link>/project/2.conservationprotectedareas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2.conservationprotectedareas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human threats – including fishing, climate change, habitat destruction, pollution, and invasive species – are leading to declining abundance of many marine species. To mitigate impacts of these threats on biodiversity, marine protected areas – national parks in the ocean – are being created. As there is a global push to increase the marine protected area network coverage from 8% to potentially 20% or even 30% in the next decade, developing the science to underpin where to place these reserves is critical and timely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A current focus of our research is thus how to design robust climate-smart marine protected areas that conserve biodiversity, protect against climate change, retain biodiversity as the climate warms, ensure connectivity, minimise conflict with fishing, whilst considering the 3-D nature of the ocean. This is a tough task! It requires extensive computational expertise and infrastructure. Our work involves mapping global biodiversity and developing new approaches to the design of climate-smart marine protected area networks using state-of-the-art statistical and computational approaches on super-computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
